<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">vonNeumann-Torvalds</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="von_neumann_name">John von Neumann</string>
    <string name="torvalds_name">Linus Torvalds</string>
    <string name="von_neumann_picture">Von Neumann in the 1940s</string>
    <string name="torvalds_picture">Torvalds in 2002</string>
    <string name="von_neumann_bio">
        John von Neumann (December 28, 1903 – February 8, 1957) was a Hungarian-American pure 
        and applied mathematician and polymath. He made major contributions to a number of fields,
        including mathematics (foundations of mathematics, functional analysis, ergodic theory, geometry, 
        topology, and numerical analysis), physics (quantum mechanics, hydrodynamics, and fluid dynamics), 
        economics (game theory), computer science (Von Neumann architecture, linear programming, 
        self-replicating machines, stochastic computing), and statistics. He was a pioneer of 
        the application of operator theory to quantum mechanics, in the development of functional analysis, 
        a principal member of the Manhattan Project and the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton 
        (as one of the few originally appointed), and a key figure in the development of game theory
        and the concepts of cellular automata, the universal constructor, and the digital computer. \n
        
        Von Neumann\'s mathematical analysis of the structure of self-replication preceded the 
        discovery of the structure of DNA. In a short list of facts about his life he submitted 
        to the National Academy of Sciences, he stated \"The part of my work I consider most essential 
        is that on quantum mechanics, which developed in Göttingen in 1926, and subsequently in Berlin 
        in 1927–1929. Also, my work on various forms of operator theory, Berlin 1930 and Princeton 1935–1939; 
        on the ergodic theorem, Princeton, 1931–1932.\" Along with Hungarian-born American theoretical 
        physicist Edward Teller and Polish mathematician Stanislaw Ulam, von Neumann worked out 
        key steps in the nuclear physics involved in thermonuclear reactions and the hydrogen bomb. 
        Von Neumann wrote 150 published papers in his life; 60 in pure mathematics, 20 in physics, 
        and 60 in applied mathematics. His last work, an unfinished manuscript written while in the 
        hospital and later published in book form as The Computer and the Brain, gives an indication 
        of the direction of his interests at the time of his death.\n
		Source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_von_Neumann
    </string>
    <string name="torvalds_bio">
        Linus Benedict Torvalds (born December 28, 1969) is a Finnish American software engineer, 
        who was the principal force behind the development of the Linux kernel. He later became 
        the chief architect of the Linux kernel, and now acts as the project\'s coordinator. 
        He also created the revision control system Git as well as the diving log software Subsurface. 
        He was honored, along with Shinya Yamanaka, with the 2012 Millennium Technology Prize by 
        the Technology Academy Finland \"in recognition of his creation of a new open source operating 
        system for computers leading to the widely used Linux kernel\".\n
        
        Torvalds attended the University of Helsinki between 1988 and 1996, graduating with a master\'s 
        degree in computer science from NODES research group. His academic career was interrupted after 
        his first year of study when he joined the Finnish Army, selecting the 11-month officer 
        training program to fulfill the mandatory military service of Finland. In the army he held 
        the rank of second lieutenant, with the role of a ballistic calculation officer. In 1990, 
        he resumed his university studies, and was exposed to UNIX for the first time, in the form of 
        a DEC MicroVAX running ULTRIX. His M.Sc. thesis was titled Linux: A Portable Operating System.
		His interest in computers began with a Commodore VIC-20. After the VIC-20 he purchased 
		a Sinclair QL, which he modified extensively, especially its operating system. 
		He programmed an assembly language and a text editor for the QL, as well as a few games. 
		He is known to have written a Pac-Man clone named Cool Man. On January 5, 1991 he purchased 
		an Intel 80386-based IBM PC before receiving his MINIX copy, which in turn enabled him 
		to begin work on Linux.\n
		Source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds
    </string>
    
</resources>
